<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Benjamin Geer</title>
    <link>https://benjamingeer.name/en/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Benjamin Geer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://benjamingeer.name/en/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tondauer</title>
      <link>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/tondauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/tondauer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I started a project called &lt;a href=&#34;https://tondauer.art/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tondauer&lt;/a&gt;, to make Creative Commons licensed editions of sheet music. It happened because of the Covid-19 lockdown in 2020: I was learning to play &lt;a href=&#34;https://tondauer.art/2021/03/mendelssohn-prelude-mwv-u-123/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Felix Mendelssohn&amp;rsquo;s Prelude Op. 104a, No. 2 (MWV U 123)&lt;/a&gt;, because it suited my mood of restless frustration at the time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started with a 19th-century edition that could be downloaded for free. Then I bought an edition with fingerings, and wondered why it had different notes. I looked in vain for the composer&amp;rsquo;s manuscript, but found only an earlier draft. I had been reading R. Larry Todd&amp;rsquo;s biography of Mendelssohn, so I emailed him to ask if he knew where the manuscript of the final version was, and he replied that it hadn&amp;rsquo;t been found. This meant that the only sources were the first editions, which were published after the composer&amp;rsquo;s death.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had learned something about how critical editions are made while working in the field of digital humanities. So I decided to make my own critical edition. Over several months, as libraries and archives gradually reopened, I got digital reproductions of the first German and British editions. The two editors had worked together to publish them simultaneously, but they didn&amp;rsquo;t have the same notes, either. In my edition, I tried to make a plausible explanation of what had happened, and reconstruct the composer&amp;rsquo;s intentions as well as possible. In the end I tried to make the edition I wished I had had, and added fingerings with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roskellacademy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Penelope Roskell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with musicologist Florence Launay on editions of forgotten works by female composers, starting with Armande de Polignac&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://tondauer.art/2022/10/polignac-preludes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Preludes for Piano&lt;/a&gt;, which had survived only in a single copy of the first edition, preserved by her descendants. Florence had photocopied it, and pianists had been recording the pieces using photocopies of that photocopy. Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve published a corrected edition with Florence&amp;rsquo;s preface, I hope more pianists will enjoy playing these Preludes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>accicalc</title>
      <link>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/accicalc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/accicalc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a program that makes spreadsheets of data about traffic accidents in France: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/benjamingeer/accicalc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;accicalc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SocioResources</title>
      <link>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/socioresources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/socioresources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://socioresources.net/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;My old blog&lt;/a&gt; (2013-2021) on the sociology of autonomy and the autonomy of sociology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>أبحاث لفتت نظري</title>
      <link>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/abhath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/abhath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My old Arabic blog (2009-2014) on which I summarised research that I thought was interesting: &lt;a href=&#34;https://benjamingeer.blogspot.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;أبحاث لفتت نظري&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>كوكبنا</title>
      <link>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/kawkabna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://benjamingeer.name/en/post/kawkabna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My occasional Arabic-language podcast (since 2021) on ecology, migration, and inequality: &lt;a href=&#34;https://%d9%83%d9%88%d9%83%d8%a8%d9%86%d8%a7.%d8%b4%d8%a8%d9%83%d8%a9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;كوكبنا.شبكة&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
